A Guide to the Papers of Albert Erskine, 1930-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Albert Erskine 1930-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
13497
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Albert Erskine Papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Marisa B. Erskine and Silvia F. Erskine, Redding, Connecticut on December 29, 2005.
Biographical/Historical Information
Albert Russel Erskine, Jr. was born in Memphis, Tennessee on April 19, 1911, and received his bachelor's degree from Southwestern College in Memphis in 1932. He then enrolled in Vanderbilt University (1932-1933) and completed his course work for his Master's degree but did not complete his thesis until 1939. In between finishing his degree, Erskine ran a bookshop, The Three Musketeers in Memphis, until Robert Penn Warren helped him secure an academic position at the Louisiana State University English Department in the fall of 1934.
When The Southern Review began in July 1935, Albert Erskine was listed as the business manager but he played a much larger role in the magazine than that. He also served as an editorial assistant for the Louisiana State University Press while living in Baton Rouge. In 1940, Erskine left LSU for New Directions Publishing, Norfolk, Connecticut, where he remained for about a year until he moved to The Saturday Review of Literature as advertising manager in December 1941. He began his job with Doubleday, Doran and Company, Inc. shortly thereafter and was subsequently hired by Reynal and Hitchcock from October 1943 until February 1947, serving as director of production and design as well as being a member of the editorial department. Erskine was on the staff of Random House from 1947 until 1976, when he retired from full-time work. He did not retire completely until 1987. Some of the first authors that Erskine worked with at Random House included Karl Shapiro, Ralph Ellison, and Robert Penn Warren. He also did a lot of work with William Faulkner and authors writing about Faulkner, as well as many of the books by James Michener. From the late fifties until his death, Erskine was married to Marisa Bisi and they had one daughter Silvia. He had previously been married to Katherine Anne Porter (1938-1942) from whom he separated in 1940, and Peggy Griffin Anthony (1942-1951).
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the editorial files of Random House editor Albert Erskine (1911-1993), ca. 1930-1999, ca. 10,500 items, 42 Hollinger boxes (ca. 17.5 linear feet) including correspondence with Random House staff and authors; editorial fact sheets and editorial notes; front and back flap copy for individual books; financial documents such as contracts, royalties, etc.; copies of articles, speeches, and book manuscripts by Random House authors; photographs of authors; reviews, advertising schedules, and publicity for book publications. Also present are some folders of personal correspondence, miscellaneous correspondence while on staff at Random House, and correspondence while Erskine was on the staff of The Southern Review in Louisiana.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in four series: Series I: William Faulkner and Books concerning William Faulkner Editorial Files (Boxes 1-9); Series II: James A. Michener Editorial Files (Boxes 10-20); Series III: Miscellaneous Authors Editorial Files (Boxes 21-39); and Series IV: Personal Correspondence and Topical Files (Boxes 39-42). Within each series, folders are arranged alphabetically by folder heading, usually by the name of the author or correspondent and chronologically within each folder.
Contents List
- Series I: William Faulkner and Books concerning William Faulkner
  - Subseries A: William Faulkner
    - William Faulkner- Articles and Short Stories, 1932-1965, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Included are: a copy of Contempo (Volume I, Number 17, 1932), "whole issue by William Faulkner"; typescript copy and the printed article Mr. Acarius by William Faulkner, with introduction by Joseph Blotner, published in The Saturday Evening Post (1965); and a copy of Mississippi by William Faulkner appearing in Holiday Magazine with an introduction by Malcolm Cowley [1961].
    - William Faulkner- Articles concerning Faulkner, 1932, 1958-1987 (Box-folder 1:2)
      Authors include: Richard P. Adams, Warren Beck, H.H. Bell, Jr., Calvin S. Brown, Robert Cantwell, Jim Cleveland, Louis Cockran, Carvel Collins, Elizabeth M. Kerr, James B. Meriwether, and Rebecca Meriwether.
    - William Faulkner- Articles concerning Faulkner, 1956-1987 (Box-folder 1:3)
      Authors include: Michael Millgate, Philip Momberger, Noel Polk, Lawrence Schwartz, Jean Stein, Olga W. Vickery, Hyatt H. Waggoner, Edward C. Wallace, Jr., and Robert Webking.
    - William Faulkner- As I Lay Dying, [1963], Corrected Setting Copy for New Edition (Marked up Print Copy). (Box-folder 1:4)
    - William Faulkner- As I Lay Dying, 1963 October 24, Author's Galley Proof, with corrections and changes, 86 sheets (oversize). (Oversize 1)
    - William Faulkner- As I Lay Dying, 1963 October 28, Plate Galley Proof, 86 sheets (oversize). (Oversize 1)
    - William Faulkner- Character Index for the Stories and Novels of Faulkner by Cleanth Brooks, 1963 June 29 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - William Faulkner- Character List for the Novels of Faulkner by Cleanth Brooks, n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - William Faulkner- Collection at the University of Virginia, 1959, 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 1:7)
      Includes photographs of the Barrett Room, a program for the exhibit William Faulkner Man Working 1919-1959, a Master List of William Faulkner Manuscripts and News Notes describing additions to the Faulkner material, and a copy of a 41 page fragment of a variant text for section 2 (June 2 1910) of The Sound and the Fury (see Mss 6271-al).
    - William Faulkner- Correspondence (Copies), 1927-1938 (Box-folder 2:1)
      Much of the original correspondence of William Faulkner with Random House editors and staff was previously given to Special Collections under the accession 10280, etc. For the originals of the earlier Horace Liveright correspondence see MSS 8171, University of Virginia Special Collections.
    - William Faulkner- Correspondence (Copies), 1939-1941 (Box-folder 2:2)
      Much of the original correspondence of William Faulkner with Random House editors and staff was previously given to Special Collections under the accession 10280, etc.
    - William Faulkner- Correspondence (Copies), 1942-1946 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - William Faulkner- Correspondence (Copies), 1947-1949 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - William Faulkner- Correspondence (Copies), 1950-1954 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - William Faulkner- Correspondence (Copies), 1955-1957 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - William Faulkner- Correspondence (Copies), 1958-1962 (Box-folder 2:7)
    - William Faulkner- Correspondence concerning Faulkner, 1960-67, 1978-85 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - William Faulkner- Estate, 1962-1975 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - William Faulkner- Estate, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - William Faulkner- Estate- W.W. Norton Agreement, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 3:3)
    - William Faulkner- Faulkner, A Comprehensive Guide to the Brodsky Collection, 1983 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - William Faulkner- Flags in the Dust Introduction,1973 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - William Faulkner- Genealogy Notes for Characters in Novels, etc. by Cleanth Brooks, with correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - William Faulkner- The Hamlet, Correspondence concerning, 1939-40, 1956-60, Copies. (Box-folder 3:7)
    - William Faulkner- The Hamlet, n.d. (Box-folder 3:8)
      James B. Meriwether's Marked Copy of the Printed Text.
    - William Faulkner- The Mansion Correspondence (copies), 1959-1960 (Box-folder 3:9)
      Editorial Notes and Foreword by Faulkner (copy).
    - William Faulkner- Miscellany, 1930-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 3:10)
    - William Faulkner- Obituaries, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:11)
    - William Faulkner- Photographs of Oxford, Mississippi and Scenes related to Faulkner, 1973 (Box-folder 3:12)
    - William Faulkner- Pylon, [1935], Printed Sheets of the First Signature and Dust Jacket, with a note dated August 25, 1965. (Box-folder 3:13)
    - William Faulkner- The Reivers A Reminiscence, n.d., Typescript Copy, Pages 1-193, with a black Harold Ober Associates cover. (Box-folder 4:1)
    - William Faulkner- The Reivers A Reminiscence, n.d., Typescript Copy, Pages 194-370, with a black Harold Ober Associates cover. (Box-folder 4:2)
    - William Faulkner- The Reivers A Reminiscence, 1962, Book-of-the-Month Club Report and a magazine excerpt published in Esquire. (Box-folder 4:3)
    - William Faulkner- Reviews, 1966-1986, n.d., Reviews chiefly of The Sound and the Fury and Father Abraham. (Box-folder 4:4)
    - William Faulkner- The Sound and the Fury (New Corrected Edition), [1984?], Copy of the Printed Text from the Second Printing February 1931 with edit markings by James B. Meriwether (Copy). (Box-folder 4:5)
    - William Faulkner- The Sound and the Fury (New Corrected Edition), [1984?], Copy of the Printed Text from the Second Printing February 1931 with edit markings by James B. Meriwether (Copy), with additional green and red pencil editing notes by Albert Erskine. (Box-folder 4:6)
    - William Faulkner- The Sound and the Fury (New Corrected Edition), [1984?], Copy of the Printed Text from the Third Printing November 1931, with additional green and red pencil editing notes by Albert Erskine and a copy of the typed manuscript for the Benjy section. (Box-folder 4:7)
    - William Faulkner- The Sound and the Fury(New Corrected Edition), [1984?], Copy of the Printed Text from the Third Printing November 1931, with additional green and red pencil editing notes by Albert Erskine and a copy of the typed manuscript for the Quentin section. (Box-folder 5:1)
    - William Faulkner- The Sound and the Fury (New Corrected Edition), [1984?], Copy of the Printed Text from the Third Printing November 1931, with additional green and red pencil editing notes by Albert Erskine and a copy of the typed manuscript for the Jason section. (Box-folder 5:2)
    - William Faulkner- The Sound and the Fury (New Corrected Edition), [1984?], Copy of the Printed Text from the Third Printing November 1931, with additional green and red pencil editing notes by Albert Erskine and a copy of the typed manuscript for the Dilsey section. (Box-folder 5:3)
    - William Faulkner- The Sound and the Fury (New, Corrected Edition), 1983-1984, Editorial Notes. (Box-folder 5:4)
    - William Faulkner- The Sound and the Fury, 1958-1965, 1981, Textual History Articles and Notes. (Box-folder 4:5)
    - William Faulkner- Speeches, including the Nobel Prize Award Speech (copy), 1950, 1961, n.d., Faulkner on Truth and Freedom excerpts from remarks made on a trip to Manila, Philippines, and Remarks by William Faulkner on Receiving from the Venezuelan Government the Andres Bello Decoration, Caracas, Venezuela. (Box-folder 5:6)
    - William Faulkner The Unvanquished, 1965, Printed Sheets of the First Signature. (Box-folder 5:7)
    - William Faulkner The Wishing Tree Correspondence, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 5:8)
    - William Faulkner The Wishing Tree Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 5:9)
    - William Faulkner The Wishing Tree, 1966-1967, Editorial Notes, Fact Sheet, Front and Back Flap Copy, and Dust Jacket. (Box-folder 5:10)
    - William Faulkner The Wishing Tree, 1964, Typed Manuscript. (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Subseries B: Books concerning William Faulkner
    - Joseph Blotner- Correspondence, 1965, 1968-1986 (Box-folder 6:1)
    - Joseph Blotner- Correspondence, 1987-1990, 1996, n.d. (Box-folder 6:2)
      Correspondence, much of it about his proposed biography of Robert Penn Warren.
    - Joseph Blotner- Faulkner A Biography, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 6:3)
      Correspondence.
    - Joseph Blotner- Faulkner A Biography, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 6:4)
    - Joseph Blotner- Faulkner A Biography, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6:5)
    - Joseph Blotner- Faulkner A Biography, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 6:6)
    - Joseph Blotner- Faulkner A Biography, [1974] (Box-folder 6:7)
      Miscellany, including blurbs for the book and several photographs of Faulkner and others, possibly used in the book.
    - Joseph Blotner- Faulkner A Biography (One Volume Edition), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6:8)
    - Joseph Blotner and Frederick L. Gwynn (Editors)- Faulkner in the University, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 6:9)
    - Joseph Blotner- Flags in the Dust, 1985 (Box-folder 6:10)
      Introduction for the Garland Facsimile Series.
    - Joseph Blotner (Editor)- Selected Letters of William Faulkner, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 6:11)
    - Joseph Blotner (Editor)- Selected Letters of William Faulkner, 1977-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 6:12)
    - Joseph Blotner (Editor)- Uncollected Stories of William Faulkner, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 7:1)
    - Joseph Blotner (Editor)- Uncollected Stories of William Faulkner, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 7:2)
    - Joseph Blotner (Editor)- Uncollected Stories of William Faulkner, 1979, Front Matter, Jacket Design and Flap Copy. (Box-folder 7:3)
    - Joseph Blotner (Editor)- Uncollected Stories of William Faulkner, n.d., Manuscripts of Stories (Copies). (Box-folder 7:4)
    - Calvin S. Brown- Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 7:5)
      Correspondence concerning an idea for a book on Faulkner aphorisms and folk witticisms.
    - Matthew J. Bruccoli- Notes, n.d. (Box-folder 7:6)
      Notes for possible corrections in Requiem for a Nun.
    - Carvel Collins- Correspondence, 1969, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 7:7)
      Discussion of his plan to combine Early Prose & Poetry with New Orleans Sketches in a single volume (1984) and the new Random House edition of Faulkner's Absalom, Absalom! Prepared by Noel Polk (1984)
    - Malcolm Cowley- The Faulkner-Cowley File: Letters and Memories, 1944-1962, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 7:8)
    - Joseph L. Fant and Robert Ashley (editors) Faulkner at West Point, 1962-1964, 1974 (Box-folder 7:9)
    - Michel Gresset- [Fascination: Faulkner's Fiction, 1919-1936 ?], 1982-1984, Includes correspondence and partial typescript. (Box-folder 7:10)
    - James B. Meriwether- Correspondence, 1959-1963 July (Box-folder 7:11)
      Includes a letter discussing Faulkner's death (August 9, 1962).
    - James B. Meriwether- Correspondence, 1963 August-1964 July (Box-folder 8:1)
    - James B. Meriwether- Correspondence, 1964 August-1965 (Box-folder 8:2)
    - James B. Meriwether (editor)- Essays, Speeches & Public Letters by William Faulkner, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 8:3)
      Correspondence and Editorial File.
    - James B. Meriwether (editor)- Essays, Speeches & Public Letters by William Faulkner, 1966-1970, 1982 (Box-folder 8:4)
    - James B. Meriwether (editor)- Essays, Speeches & Public Letters by William Faulkner, ca. 1965 (Box-folder 8:5)
      Essay Section, Manufacturing Schedule, and Table of Contents.
    - James B. Meriwether (editor)- Essays, Speeches & Public Letters by William Faulkner, ca. 1965 (Box-folder 8:6)
      Speeches Section.
    - James B. Meriwether (editor)- Essays, Speeches & Public Letters by William Faulkner, ca. 1965 (Box-folder 8:7)
      Introduction, Book Reviews and Public Letters Sections, and Corrected Pages.
    - Michael Millgate- The Achievement of William Faulkner,1966 (Box-folder 8:8)
      Chapter on The Sound and the Fury with cuts and letter of explanation from [Robert Penn Warren].
    - Michael Millgate- The Achievement of William Faulkner, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8:9)
      Correspondence, including the plan for the book (January 24, 1963); contract with Random House (May 2, 1963); correspondence with Ben Glazebrook, Constable Publishers, about the book's publication in Great Britain (throughout 1963-1965).
    - Michael Millgate- The Achievement of William Faulkner, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Michael Millgate- The Achievement of William Faulkner, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 9:1)
      Editorial Notes and Book Production Information.
    - Michael Millgate- The Achievement of William Faulkner,1966 (Box-folder 9:2)
      Reviews.
    - Michael Millgate- The Lion in the Garden: Interviews with William Faulkner (with James B. Meriwether), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 9:3)
      Correspondence, including contract information (September 23, 30; October 6, 1966).
    - Michael Millgate- The Lion in the Garden: Interviews with William Faulkner (with James B. Meriwether), 1968 (Box-folder 9:4)
    - Michael Millgate- The Lion in the Garden: Interviews with William Faulkner (with James B. Meriwether), 1967-1970 (Box-folder 9:5)
      Editorial Notes and Book Production Information, including the introduction, dust jacket, and profit and loss statements.
    - Michael Millgate- The Lion in the Garden: Interviews with William Faulkner (with James B. Meriwether), 1966-1968 (Box-folder 9:6)
      Permissions (1966-1967) and Reviews (1968).
    - Michael Millgate- The Reivers, 1985 (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Noel Polk- Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 9:8)
      Includes notes on Sanctuary (1978); a collation of the typescript setting copy of Absalom, Absalom against the first edition (June 15, 1981); and correspondence where Polk agrees to work with Random House on new corrected editions of Absalom, Absalom and The Sound and the Fury (September 27, 1982; December 7, 1982; August 28, 1984; March 22, 1985); and copies of his work appearing in The Southern Review (Fall 1982)
    - Noel Polk- Correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 9:9)
      (See some references to later dates above.)
    - Elisabeth Schnack- Correspondence concerning the translating of William Faulkner into German, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 9:10)
    - Judith Sensibar- Correspondence concerning the poetry of William Faulkner, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 9:11)
- Series II: James A. Michener
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 10:1)
    Correspondence, Fact Sheet, etc.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 10:2)
    Editing Notes, Typescript Copies, and Research Material for Chapter 1.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 10:3)
    Editing Notes for Chapters 2-4.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 10:4)
    Editing Notes for Chapters 5-7.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 10:5)
    Editing Notes for Chapters 8-9.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 10:6)
    Editing Notes for Chapters 10-12.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1988 (Box-folder 10:7)
    Fact and Fiction Synopsis and Acknowledgments Editing Notes.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1988 February 9 (Box-folder 11:1)
    Edited Page Proofs of Front Matter and Chapters 1-3.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1988 February 9 (Box-folder 11:2)
    Edited Page Proofs of Chapters 4-5.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1988 February 9, Edited Page Proofs of Chapters 6-7. (Box-folder 11:3)
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1988 February 9 (Box-folder 11:4)
    Edited Page Proofs of Chapter 8.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1988 (Box-folder 11:5)
    Manuscript of the Canadian Version, Chapter 8, which includes the MacKenzie River segment cut from the United States version.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1988 February 9 (Box-folder 11:6)
    Edited Page Proofs of Chapters 9-10.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1988 February 9 (Box-folder 11:7)
    Edited Page Proofs of Chapter 11.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1988 February 9 (Box-folder 12:1)
    Edited Page Proofs of Chapter 12.
  - James A. Michener- Alaska, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 12:2)
    Maps and Chapter Head Drawings.
  - James A. Michener- Art Collection described in Private Affinities and Public Uses: The Michener Collection by Richard Hirsch in Arts Magazine, 1966 May, (Printed). (Box-folder 12:3)
  - James A. Michener- Art Collection at the University of Texas at Austin in Texas Quarterly, Vol. 13, No. 1, 1970 Spring, (Printed) (Box-folder 12:3a)
  - James A. Michener- Articles concerning Israel, 1967 (Box-folder 12:4)
  - James A. Michener- Biographical Information, n.d. (Box-folder 12:5)
  - James A. Michener- The Bridge at Andau, 1956-1968 (Box-folder 12:6)
  - James A. Michener- The Bridges at Toko-ri, 1953-1972, 2003 (Box-folder 12:7)
    Includes an article by Warren E. Thompson- "The Reality Behind Toko-Ri."
  - James A. Michener- Caravans, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 12:8)
  - James A. Michener- Caribbean, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 12:9)
  - James A. Michener- Centennial, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 12:10)
    This file includes the Book-of-the-Month club report on the book, the dust jacket, profit and loss statement, and a poster.
  - James A. Michener- In Search of Centennial: A Journey with James A. Michener by John Kings, 1978, 1980 (Box-folder 12:11)
    Includes a foreword by Michener and an undated contract for a possible biography of Michener by Kings.
  - James A. Michener- Chesapeake, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 12:12)
  - James A. Michener- Chesapeake Diary, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 13:1)
    Original Manuscript with red pencil corrections and penciled page number changes.
  - James A. Michener- Chesapeake Diary, 1974-1978, Copies. (Box-folder 13:2)
  - James A. Michener- Contracts with Random House and the William Morris Agency, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 13:3)
  - James A. Michener- Correspondence, 1948-1962 (Box-folder 13:4)
  - James A. Michener- Correspondence, 1963-1988, 1991 (Box-folder 13:5)
    Includes miscellaneous financial information concerning Michener's books.
  - James A. Michener- The Covenant, 1978-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 13:6)
  - James A. Michener- The Drifters, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 13:7)
    Book Outline and Production Material.
  - James A. Michener- The Drifters, Correspondence and Reviews, 1969-1972, 1978 (Box-folder 13:8)
    Includes progress report (August 31, 1969; March 1 and 24, 1970); the sale of the first serial right to The Ladies Home Journal (June 30, 1970); British version (November 16, 1970); Book-of-the-Month Club selection (November 11 and 17, 1970); German version (February 18, 1971); and the Fawcett paperback edition (May 8, 1972).
  - James A. Michener- The Drifters, 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 13:9)
    Editing Notes and Research Material.
  - James A. Michener- Facing East Introduction, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 13:10)
  - James A. Michener- Facing East, 1970, Introduction Typescript and copy of proof. (Box-folder 14:1)
  - James A. Michener- The Fires of Spring, 1948-49, 1962-72 (Box-folder 14:2)
    Includes correspondence with Saxe Commins about becoming a Random House author while still employed at MacMillan and negotiations with President George P. Brett, Jr. for release from his contract.
  - James A. Michener- The Floating World, 1954-1965 (Box-folder 14:3)
    Includes a letter from Michener while in Saigon, Viet Nam, which discusses the unsettled conditions there and his opinion of the review (attached to the letter) of The Floating World by Leslie A. Fiedler (July 24, 1955).
  - James A. Michener- Greeting Cards, Post cards, and Photographs, Ca. 1956-1980, n.d. (Box-folder 14:4)
  - James A. Michener- Hawaii, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 14:5)
    Includes letters from Erskine full of editing notes about the book (March-April 1959) and two references to a proposed visit from William Faulkner to go over his book, which was prevented by Faulkner's fall from his horse (March 21 and 27, 1959); problems with the names of Chinese characters and genealogical charts (March 31 and April 3 and 6, 1959).
  - James A. Michener- Hawaii, 1960-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 14:6)
  - James A. Michener- Iberia Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 14:7)